A Guide to the Edward Rowland Sill Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7940-a
Edward Rowland Sill Collection
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7940-a
9 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1967 Feb 20
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem, " The Dawn ", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p. (initialed)
  - Poem, " To My Correspondent who writes of the Weather ", Printed(initialed)
    [Signed, with note.]
  - Last page of manuscript, 1866 Feb 19; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Begins "... word to be removed be 'haggard'.. ."]
  - Fragment of manuscript, n. d.; AMs, 1 p.
    [Begins ".. .we are tolerable at present"]
  - Resume of Sill's life, n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Edward Rowland Sill to [Elizabeth Stuart Phelps] Ward, 1886 Jun 28; ALS, 4 p.
    [Responds to her request that he read and judge [
    The Wind of Destiny
    ], which she sent to him; says he likes the author, but not the book.]
  - Edward Rowland Sill to [Elizabeth Stuart Phelps] Ward, 1886 Nov 6; ALS, 4 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of [
    The Madonna of the Tubs
    ?]; says he is impressed with the cover, the sketches, and most of all, the "Thing Itself."]
  - Edward Rowland Sill to [Elizabeth Stuart Phelps] Ward, 1887 Jan 30; ALS, 4 p.
    [Wishes her a speedy recovery from an injured foot; comments on his own health; says he and his wife are enjoying their holiday in New York, opera, chamber music concerts, art exhibits, etc.; finds Rev. and Mrs. Gilder an interesting pair; inquires if she has been to New York and if she knows the literary people there.]
- Photograph
  - Edward Rowland Sill, head and shoulders, [1861]; Photo
    [Autographed.]